Guide to the Marine Workers Historical Collection TAM.125
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Marine Workers Historical Collection
1930-1996
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Weiner, Morris
Szeliga, Loretta
Doyle, Joe
Green, Thomas
Marine Workers Historical Association (U.S.)
Peterson, T. H.
Bouvier, Libby
TAM.125
3.75 Linear Feet in 4 record cartons and one folder.
The Marine Workers Historical Collection was the result of a community history project on the Chelsea area of New York City conducted by Joe Doyle, then a New York University Department of Public History graduate student, beginning in 1981. Doyle set out to reconstruct and document the working-class population and institutions of the Chelsea waterfront of New York City in the first half of the twentieth century. The project was continued and expanded in partnership with the Marine Workers Historical Association. The collection includes rank-and-file newsletters, flyers, union correspondence, grievance reports, pamphlets, memoirs, memorabilia and printed ephemera of many kinds documenting the working and living conditions of American merchant seamen/women since 1900 and the struggle of maritime workers, particularly sympathizers of the Left, to organize and maintain leadership in the National Maritime Union (NMU) and other unions.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The material in this collection was donated to the Tamiment Library as a result of collecting efforts by Joe Doyle, working with the Marine Workers Historical Association, in a series of donations from 1982-2002. The accession number associated with these gifts is 1950.032.
Arrangement
Files arranged alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Marine Workers Historical Collection was the result of a community history project on the Chelsea area of New York City conducted by Joe Doyle, then a New York University Department of Public History graduate student, beginning in 1981. Doyle set out to reconstruct and document the working-class population and institutions of the Chelsea waterfront of New York City in the first half of the twentieth century. Chelsea was a center of shipping and there was a sizable Irish presence in the area. Through walking tours, lectures, plays and locally published articles, Doyle examined the role of Irish politicians and maritime workers in the fabric of a neighborhood. Through oral history interviews, he learned that many founders of the National Maritime Union shipped out from the hiring halls of Chelsea. Doyle's grant application, project reports and an article in Public History(Vol. I, l984) explain the difficulties of trying to research the maritime history of a community that in some instances did not want that history written. During his second year of work on the project Doyle joined forces with the Marine Workers Historical Association, which was actively collecting documentary material.
In 1979, some sixty former seamen and longshoremen had formed the Marine Workers Historical Association to bring together those who had been engaged in the organizing efforts on waterfront and on shipboard in the 1930s, to preserve their history through documents and written and oral accounts by participants, and to make that history more widely known. The first issue of their newsletter, The Hawsepipe(Nov Dec, 1981), included a reference to the Tamiment Library's interest in adding documents, personal histories, photographs, etc. to its archives. Because many American seamen had shipped out of the Chelsea area, Joe Doyle had included MWHA seamen in his Chelsea research activities and he became a central contact person and chief solicitor of much of the current collection. The collection continues to seek out and accept donations of material.
Related Materials
John Gladstone Papers (WAG 146)
Jake Green Photographs (PHOTOS 047)
International Longshoremen's Association: Reference Files Compiled by the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (WAG 055)
Marine Workers Oral History Collection (OH 030)
National Maritime Union Photographs (PHOTOS 044)
National Maritime Union and Seafarers International Union: Reference Files of the Seafarers International Union (WAG 267)
New Yorkers at Work Oral History Collection (OH 001)
Clarence Reed Papers (WAG 015)
Randall B. (Pete) Smith: Maritime Radicalism Collection (TAM 203)
Henry Spira Papers (TAM 418)
Scope and Content Note
The Marine Workers Historical Collection includes rank-and-file newsletters, flyers, union correspondence, grievance reports, pamphlets, memoirs, memorabilia and printed ephemera of many kinds documenting the working and living conditions of American merchant seamen/women since 1900 and the struggle of maritime workers, particularly sympathizers of the Left, to organize and maintain leadership in the National Maritime Union (NMU) and other unions.
Of particular note are files of clippings relating to NMU president Joseph Curran and critiques of the Curran administration produced by rank-and-file opposition groups and individuals. Outstanding among these is a 350-page typescript memoir by Edward Gordon entitled "Where Away." Gordon describes in detail his upbringing in a Russian immigrant family and his twenty-four years at sea. He discusses early organizing efforts, the hardships of life at sea and power struggles within the union.
A series of files documents the International Seaman's Union strike of 1936, and a small amount of material on Harry Bridges, president of the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union and Paul Hall, president of the Seamen's International Union, are also included. Notable among the rank-and-file activists whose experience is documented are Bill Bailey, Barney Lynch, Frederick N. (Blackie) Myers, Stanley Postek, and Morris Weiner. The structure and development of Joe Doyle's Chelsea Waterfront History Project and the administrative history of the Marine Workers Historical Association are also well represented in the collection.
The collection also contains some photographs of National Maritime Union members, membership books, and identification cards.
Separated Materials
In 2008 correspondence between Elinor Ferry and F.X. Boyle was separated from this collection and incorporated into the Elinor Ferry Papers (TAM 116), and a Sidney Kaufman scrapbook was transferred to the Sidney Kaufman Papers (ALBA 058).
Minutes (administrative records); Reports.; Correspondence.; Biographies.; New York (N.Y.).; Fliers (printed matter); Clippings (information artifacts); Contracts; Merchant mariners |x Labor unions |z United States.; Gladstone, John, 1917-; Weiner, Morris; Szeliga, Loretta; Doyle, Joe; International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union; Green, Thomas; International Seamen's Union of America; Wirtz, Willard, 1912-; National Maritime Union of America; Marine Cooks and Stewards Association of the Pacific Coast; Marine Workers Historical Association (U.S.); Bailey, Bill, 1911-1995; Seafarers International Union of North America; Doyle, Joe; Hall, Paul; Bridges, Harry, 1901-; Postek, Stanley, 1912-1991; Curran, Joseph Edwin, 1906-1981; Peterson, T. H.; Bouvier, Libby
- Alexander, Gus: Society's Stepchildren Fight Back!: The Story of the Scandinavian Seamen in America (pamphlet), 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Merchant Fleet Informational Pamphlet for Sailors (untitled), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bailey, Bill: Articles by and about, 1938-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bailey, Bill: "Marine Workers Historical Association Honors the Life of its President" (spiral bound book, photocopy), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bailey, Bill: "Odyssey (Voyage) of the Morning Star," Unpublished Novel (typescript), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bailey, Bill: Promotion for Autobiography, Kid from Hoboken, circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Baker, M. D.: "Tanker Strike" Card, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Boano, Danny: Drafts of Unpublished Memoirs, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Board of Inquiry on Long-shore Industry Work Stoppage, October-November 1951, Port of New York(photocopy) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bolmarcich, John P.: Letter to Pilot Editor, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bolmarcich, John P.: "Tuberculosis and Seamen" (marked up for publication in The Hawsepipe), undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bridges, Harry: Correspondence with Gil Mers, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bridges, Harry: Correspondence with Julius Margolin, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bridges, Harry: Clippings, 1936-1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bridges, Harry: Open Letter to Joseph Curran and NMU Officers about West Coast Maritime Strike, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Brooklyn Longshoremen "Outlaw" Strike: Clippings, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Chambers, Whittaker: "A Political History of a Modern Agent-Provocateur," Book Proposal, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Chelsea Waterfront History Project: Administrative, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Chelsea Waterfront History Project: Report of Commission on Industrial Relations(pp. 2053-2199), undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Chelsea Waterfront History Project: Hobo News(photocopies), undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Chelsea Waterfront History Project: Joe Doyle Publications, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Chelsea Waterfront History Project: Research Materials, undated, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Clippings, 1920s (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Clippings, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Clippings, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Clippings, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Clippings, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Clippings, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Clippings, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Copeland, Bill: "Protest the Copeland Bill" Cards, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Curran, Joseph: Clippings, 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Curran, Joseph: Clippings (I), 1960s (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Curran, Joseph: Clippings (II), 1960s (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Curran, Joseph: Clippings (III), 1960s (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Curran, Joseph: International Longshoremen's Association Longshore Election Press Release, Oct 16, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Curran, Joseph: The Membership Wins Again, National Maritime Union Pamphlet, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Curran, Joseph: "NMU President Discusses Problems of U. S. Merchant Marine," NYS Industrial Bulletin(photocopy), 1961 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Curran, Joseph: Signed letter to Daily Worker about Roy Hudson, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Curran, Joseph: "What is the Rank and File Caucus? ," Flyer (photocopy), 1946 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Curran, Joseph et al v. Morrissey and Ibrahim: Briefs, Clippings, Pamphlet, Notes, and U. S. District Court Decision, 1969-1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Daily Worker Clipping: Chalk Drawings of Noted Marine Workers (Stanley Postek, Tex Drake, Benny Foster, Ann Russell, Captain Hugh Mulzac, and Alfonse G. Wolfe), Jul 18, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Dockers News: International Longshoremen's Association Dissidents (photocopies), Mar 1951 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Forrey, Eddie: "Peace of Mind," Poetry, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Gavin, James (Jimmy): Memoirs and Poetry (unpublished), 1939-1975 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Gordon, Edward: Monograph on Maritime History in Latin America (typescript) (I), undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Gordon, Edward: Monograph (II), undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Gordon, Edward: National Maritime Union Special Representative Confirmation Letter, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Gordon, Edward: "Where Away: A Narrative by Edward Gordon," Unpublished Memoir (pages 1-122), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Gordon, Edward: "Where Away" (pages 123-224), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Gordon, Edward: "Where Away" (pages 225-336), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Gordon, Edward: "Where Away" Research and Appendices, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Grant, George and Al Smith: Brief Biographical Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Green, Thomas (Tommy): Memoir (typescript), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Grey, Barry: Correspondence with Morris Weiner, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Hall, Paul: Clippings, 1962, 1971, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Hall, Paul: Murray Kempton Tribute, Clipping, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Hall, Paul: Telegram regarding U. S. Department of Labor Anniversary Dinner (photocopy), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Hawsepipe, Newsletter of the Marine Workers Historical Association: Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Hawsepipe: Indexes and Table of Contents, 1981-1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Hawsepipe (Vol. I, No. 1), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Hawsepipe (Vol. III, No. 4): Draft, Research, and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Hook, International Longshoremen's Association, Local 1258 Newsletter (photocopies), Aug 1934-Apr 1935 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Huberman, Leo: The NMU: What It Is, What It Does(pamphlet), 1943 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Hudson, Roy B.: Marine Workers Industrial Union Identification and Membership Book, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Industrial Union of Maritime and Shipbuilding Workers: Contract, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- International Longshore and Warehouse Union Attitude toward the Open Shop (Lundberg) Clause, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- International Organization of Masters, Mates, and Pilots Strike, Elizabethport, NJ: Flyer, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
- International Seamen's Union (ISU): Mass Protest Meeting (flyer), 1936 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- International Seamen's Union: Membership Meeting on Board the SS California(photocopies), Feb 1936 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- International Seamen's Union Strike: Appeal Addressed to "Colored Seamen," Flyer (photocopy), 1936 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- International Seamen's Union Strike: Bulletins (photocopies), 1936 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- International Seamen's Union Strike: Correspondence, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- International Seamen's Union Strike: Minutes of Various Bodies, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- International Seamen's Union Strike: Open Letters by W. B. Follett, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- International Seamen's Union Strike: Rank and File Seamen Strike (Gulf Coast) Minutes, Flyers, Newsletters, Clippings (all photocopies), 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Jones, Rose (Secretary of the South Street Strike Hall): Oral History Transcript, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Kaufman, Sidney: Shipping Papers (photocopies), 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Keith, Charles: Fund Letter and "Charles Keith, A Seaman," Obituary by Bernard Nossiter, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Kempton, Murray: Correspondence with Morris Weiner, 1949-1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Kempton, Murray: National Maritime Union Clippings, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Kramer, Jacob A.: "How Racism Was Used to Stymie Union Organizing of Great Lake Seamen" (typescript), undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Labor Research Association: "Leaders in Labor's Fight for Economic Security through a Peacetime Economy," Benefit Honoring Harry Bridges, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Lynch, Barney: Correspondence to Greta Lynch (photocopies), 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Lynch, Barney: Memorial Letter by Greta Lynch, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Lynch, Barney: Obituary Letter by Johnny Gladstone, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Lynch, Greta (Kornfeld): Biographical and General, 1943-1990 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Lynch, Greta: National Maritime Union Women's Auxiliary and Strike Cards, 1937-1946 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Lynch, Philip: Seamen's Bank Book, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Mandell, Sam: Oral History Transcript, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Margolin, Julius (Julie): Correspondence with U. S. Government and 1943 Margolin Clipping, 1943, 1966, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Marine Cooks' and Stewards' Association: Correspondence re: Members in the Spanish Civil War, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Marine Workers Historical Association: By-Laws, Draft, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Marine Workers Historical Association: "First National Gathering," Conference, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Marine Workers Historical Association: Letter to Membership (incomplete), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Marine Workers Historical Association: Membership and Contact List, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Marine Workers Historical Association: Minutes, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Marine Workers Historical Association: Norval D. Welch and Johnny Gladstone Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Marine Workers Historical Association: Walking Tour Interview, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Marine Workers Industrial Union: The Bull Line Fighter, Vol. 1-1, No. 2 (photocopy), 1932 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Maritime Federation of the Gulf Coast: Organizing (Houston Longshoremen), 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Maritime Federation of the Pacific, Educational Committee: The Yanks Are Not Coming(pamphlet), 1939 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Marx, Kathryn: Maritime Union History 1850s-1901(essay), undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
- McCarthy, Bill: Art Shields Article on, undated, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- McKenzie, Howard (National Maritime Union): Memorial Service Announcement, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Merrell, James (Blackie): Memorial Tributes by Paul J. Jarvis and Morris Weiner, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Mers, Gil: Memoir (incomplete), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Morrissey, Jim: Clippings, 1979, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Myers, Frederick (Blackie): Certificates of Discharge and Service, 1934-1950 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Myers, Blackie: Financial Records, 1935-1948 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Myers, Blackie: Handwritten Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Myers, Blackie: Obituary, The Dispatcher (photocopy), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Myers, Blackie: Personal Papers and Identification Cards, 1932-1951 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Nelles, Dieter: "I Prefer to March with the Army That's Winning," Translated with Transcribed Remarks on Richard Krebs by Jan Valtin, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
- New Bedford Strike of 1928: Clippings, Standard Times, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- National Maritime Union: "At Your Service," Personal Service Department Flyer, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
- National Maritime Union: Bookstore Catalogue "Take a Book to Bed-Too!", undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
- National Maritime Union: Clippings from the Joseph Padilla Collection, 1960s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 69)
- National Maritime Union: CIO Certificate of Affiliation (photocopy), 1938 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- National Maritime Union: Committee for Democratic Unionism Bulletin, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- National Maritime Union: Companies under Agreement with National Maritime Union, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 72)
- National Maritime Union: Engine Division Membership Book (Alex Karpowski), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- National Maritime Union: Expulsions, Clippings, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- National Maritime Union: Expulsions, Drummond v. Curran, Aurelio Decision, etc., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- National Maritime Union: Founding, 1930s (Box 2, Folder 76)
- National Maritime Union: General, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- National Maritime Union: "High Wages for Merchant Seamen?...Read the Truth," Flyer, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- National Maritime Union: "Hitler's Little Helper," Flyer in Spanish, undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
- National Maritime Union: Independent Caucus Anti-Expulsion Newsletters (Spanish and English), 1947-1951 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- National Maritime Union: National Convention Report, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- National Maritime Union: "New Revolt in the NMU," by Dorothy Day (New Republic), 1950 (Box 2, Folder 82)
- National Maritime Union: Organizing West Coast Cooks and Stewards, Summary Reports, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 83)
- National Maritime Union: Port of New York Mobilization, 1947-1951 (Box 2, Folder 84)
- National Maritime Union: Rank and File Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 85)
- National Maritime Union: Rank and File Dissent, "A Stone around the Seamen's Neck," Draft of Open Letter, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 86)
- National Maritime Union: Rank and File Dissent, Anti-Curran Open Letters and Pamphlets, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 87)
- National Maritime Union: Rank and File Dissent, Bigotry in the Union, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 88)
- National Maritime Union: Rank and File Dissent, "Has Our Constitution Been Stoned?" (typescript), undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
- National Maritime Union: Rank and File Dissent, New York Book Selling Scandal, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 90)
- National Maritime Union: Rank and File Dissent, Organizing New York Office Workers, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 91)
- National Maritime Union: Rank and File Dissent, Pension and Welfare Plan, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 92)
- National Maritime Union: Rank and File Dissent, Union Elections, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 93)
- National Maritime Union: Rank and File Dissent, Union Elections Membership Committee Ticket and Spanish Language Principles, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- National Maritime Union: Rank and File Dissent, U.S. Public Health Service Hospital Committee, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- National Maritime Union: Scrapbook (clippings), 1950-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- National Maritime Union: "Songs for Seamen," Pamphlet, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- National Maritime Union: Staff Officers Association, Open Letter, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- National Maritime Union: Stewards Department Meeting on SS Exochorda, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- National Maritime Union: United Rank and File Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- National Maritime Union: "We Keep 'Em Sailing" (poster), undated (Box Shared Tamiment MSOS004, Folder 1)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (U. S. Southern District Court) (pages 1-67), Apr 20, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 68-unnumbered), Apr 20, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts, May 1, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts, Jul 20, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 1-50), Aug 10, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 51-144), Aug 10, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 145-209), Sep 14, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 210-282), Sep 14, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 1-76), Sep 19, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 77-157), Sep 19, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 158-263), Sep 20, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 264-343), Sep 20, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 344-385), Sep 21, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 386-440), Sep 21, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 441-486), Sep 21, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 487-534), Sep 21, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 535-600), Sep 22, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 601-678), Sep 22, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 679-758), Sep 25, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- National Maritime Union: Wirtz, W. Willard v. National Maritime Union Transcripts (pages 759-854b), Sep 25, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 27)